Raghav Rastogi Full Stack .NET Developer

- raghavrastogi1990@gmail.com
- +91 8318651126
- Lucknow, India
- **#** 24/04/2000

- github.com/raghav2404
- https://leetcode.com/u/raghavrastogi1990/

Profile

Software developer with 3+ years of experience in C#, .NET Core, APIs, SQL Server, EF Core and Angular. Experienced in developing and deploying enterprisegrade microservices-based solutions in BFSI domain. Strong background in creating efficient scalable APIs, integrating with database, UI, and ensuring code quality through unit testing.



Skills

Languages And Frameworks: C# • .NET Core

- RESTful APIs ASP.NET MVC Web API Entity Framework Core • LINQ •
- Microservices HTML5 CSS3 TypeScript
- Angular Design patterns RabbitMQ

Databases: Micrososft SQL Server

Testing: Unit Testing (xUnit), Integration Testing, TDD

DevOps And Cloud: Azure Devops (CI/CD) • Openshift • Microsoft Azure

Version Control: Git

Other Tools: ELK • Postman • JIRA



Education

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science

SRM University 2018 - 2022 | Chennai CGPA:9.45/10

Class - XII(ISC)

St' Francis College 2017 - 2018 | Lucknow Secured: 90%

Professional Experience

Infosys Limited

Senior Systems Engineer 09/2023 - present | Bengaluru, India

• Strategic partnership with Infosys led to acquisition of Danske IT. Currently working for Danske Bank client within the E-LoanData team in Core Financing Platform on projects related to Remortgage and Consent management.

Danske IT and Support Services

Associate Software Engineer 07/2022 - 08/2023 | Bengaluru, India

• Contributed to the Fund Settlement Team in Market Post Trade services.

Danske IT and Support Services

Associate Software Engineer Intern 01/2022 - 07/2022 | Bengaluru, India

• Contributed to Gold Squad in Market Post Trade Services.

Certificates

- AZ900 Microsoft Azure Fundamentals
- Foundational C# with Microsoft

휴 Extra-Curricular

Campus Ambassador (CodeHive Society)

08/2020 - 05/2021

Collaborated with fellow members to create android applications like step counter and conducted workshops.

Interests

- Travelling
- Cricket



Languages

English

Hindi

Projects

Loan Monitoring and E-Loan Data

- Developed a new API version for e-Consent application that includes new endpoints for personal customers to activate and reject consents, improving consent management process.
- Contributed to development of Remortgage Evaluation service by adding EF Core for data management, REST endpoints for business logic, and integrating credit score functionality to assess remortgage potential and provide loan recommendations.
- Refactored monolithic shared service in E-LoanData into modular NuGet packages, set up repositories and CI/CD, integrated the packages into main services to enhance reusability and maintainability.
- Increased code coverage by implementing comprehensive unit tests using xUnit.
- Implemented Hangfire dashboards and jobs to process and monitor batch jobs for remortgage potential calculations and evaluations efficiently.
- Created SQL triggers for audit logging and developed SQL scripts for data migration, cleanup, and schema updates to ensure consistent and reliable database operations across services.
- Enhanced Angular based Consent UI by consuming e-Consent API endpoints via a Backend-For-Frontend and updating it to display consent details for advisors, improving functionality and user experience.
- Modified and optimized SQL views via EF Core migrations for remortgage scenarios, enabling lead generation by analytics.
- Implemented CQRS pattern using MediatR to separate read and write concerns, Repository pattern to abstract data access logic, Builder pattern to create complex domain objects with optional fields and Factory pattern to centralize object creation for services and handlers.

Free Of Payments (FOP Tool)

- Implemented migration of backend application from IIS to OpenShift,resulting in decrease in runtime, thus improving performance and scalability.
- Developed 'Fee Calculator Logic' to determine transaction fees and commissions for fund transfers based within our custody account system.
- Developed a .NET 6 solution, utilizing Quartz Scheduler and Dapper to automate cleanup of GDPR noncompliant data from history and user tables, ensuring regulatory compliance and enhancing data management efficiency across multiple teams.
- Optimized and fine-tuned sql queries to improve database interaction performance. Also implemented stored procedures, triggers and sql scripts to optimise database operations.
- Designed and implemented forms in an Angular POC for the Free of Payments UI, focusing on user-friendly interfaces to enable advisors to place transfers directly.